# **Luke Morgan - CV**

I'm a capable web developer with strong skills in UI development using React, Vue and Node.js. I also have experience with back-end coding in modern PHP & SQL (Laravel & WordPress). I have current experience with making solid contributions within agile workflows in the development of enterprise IT projects with exposure to the full software development lifecycle. In my spare time, I am currently building my skills in C#/.NET - API & MVC patterns.

### **Employment history:**

## February 2022 - Present: Junior Front-End Developer - Wiley (Madgex Ltd)

I've worked on a greenfield project in a small team of 3 developers to create a CMS, API and collection of server and client-side rendered micro frontends. I've contributed to the project by implementing and testing complex UI features documented by unit and UI component tests, reviewing and approving pull-requests, setting up code testing and test coverage tools and then using those tools to improve the CI/CD pipeline. I also work closely with the UX team to translate user feedback into new feature specifications and implement those features to drive platform improvements.

I delivered improvements to a legacy data visualisation and reporting platform built in Vue.JS. I implemented a series of complex UI feature requests to enhance the platform's existing report building capabilities as well as implementing a series of bug fixes with minimal supervision.

I've contributed to knowledge sharing with colleagues by delivering company-wide workshops on Unit testing, UI Component testing and mocking API requests in unit tests. I also regularly spend time working with the cloud based logging and monitoring service ( Datadog ). Examples of this include creating internal documentation aimed at new developers and configuring monitors and alerts in the team's communications channels relating to application performance for projects I've worked on.

I also help to extend and maintain a series of in-house internal use libraries packaged as private npm repositories.

- Enterprise UI development Vue.js/Hapi.js/GraphQL.
- Client-side state management patterns with Vuex/Pinia.
- Unit testing with Vitest, Vue Test Utils and Mock Service Worker.
- Experience developing with a11y, i18n and OWASP Top 10 considerations.
- Experience with agile delivery on legacy and greenfield projects full SDLC.

#### May 2021 - Present: Contract PHP/SQL Developer

I am the technical lead for a WordPress plugin that is used by publishers to generate branded HTML email newsletter templates driven by content from their WordPress website. The plugin also integrates with a range of email marketing platforms to enable end-to-end automation of HTML email newsletter campaign creation from inside the WordPress CMS admin screen.

#### See enterprise use case study:

https://uplandsoftware.com/adestra/wp-content/uploads/sites/33/2019/11/case-study-tjc.pdf

I refactored two Laravel websites for an EU based precision manufactuer. I updated the Laravel framework from version 5.7 => 8.x. The framework changes were so consequential that it involved a complete rewrite of database schema, data-modelling, view template logic and static asset bundling behind each website. I also updated the admin system to support user roles, verified admin user signups by invite-only, password management and implemented some authorization middleware to secure admin routes based on the authenticated admin user's role.

I created an PHP/MySQL enquiry management system for a music technology company's WordPress website. The system integrates with the Ninja Forms WordPress plugin and then uses WP-Cron to generate a series of emails and database transactions based on the status of each enquiry record and respond to these in a time-sensitive manner. The system sends out emails to customers, suppliers and internal staff with the overall goal of providing business intelligence on how well customer enquiries are being handled by their internationally distributed supplier network.

I created a factory operation line check in/check out system using PHP/SQLite and JavaScript. The system was used to record the times that lanes within the production line were in operation by factory line staff and which lanes were active at any one time.

I created a series of PHP/MySQL webforms to handle external dental referrals and patient sign-ups for a Dental practice's website. The forms featured client and server-side form validation with submission history, admin-only HTML to PDF downloads for internal use; email notifications on submission and secure data and file storage.

# July 2021 - January 2022: Web Developer - Two Hours Sleep

I worked here as a full-stack web developer with an emphasis on backend coding. My role was mostly creating custom solutions in PHP/MySQL packaged as WordPress plugin or Theme components.

Examples of projects I worked on were a series of custom LMS solutions for content creators to plug into their WordPress websites. One allowed the creator to create and offer protected learning content and measure their users progress through the content. The solution had to be integrated with an existing membership management solution available in the WordPress ecosystem that the client's website was already using.

Another example allowed the content creator to create an end-of-lesson quiz in the admin section of their website which would be rendered as a html form on the front-end all using a complete no-code solution. The answers to the quizzes were saved in a MySQL database and students could also download their answers and results as a PDF file.

#### July 2019 - July 2021: Web Developer - The Jamieson Consultancy

I started here as a junior web developer initially working on bespoke html-email templates. I quickly upskilled myself to become a confident front-end developer gaining more competence with HTML, CSS and JavaScript. My duties expanded to building out a series of custom built PHP WordPress brochure websites.

Alongside web-development tasks, I was also trusted to deliver the creation of digital magazines for 5 separate brands following a year-round digital production schedule for each brand.

I broadened my skills beyond front-end web development tasks and also spent time working on database administrator tasks such as generating SQL queries and statistics from verbal or written business requirements, technical search engine optimization and also gained experience in linux server administration.

- Web development PHP/SQL HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- WordPress Theme and Plugin development.
- Database administration Microsoft Access/SQL.
- Bespoke HTML E-mail templating for the UK/European manufacturing industry.
- Delivered a digital production schedule for 5 magazine brands.

# September 2018 - November 2018: Intern - Neptune Media

• Short internship at a small web design and hosting company. Gained some foundational knowledge in web development and design.

# October 2014 - January 2018: Healthcare support worker - NHS

• General healthcare support-work with adults in a variety of NHS acute and non-acute health-care settings.

# **Education history:**

September 2011- May 2013: Bexhill Sixth Form College - BTEC Diploma

Subject	Grade
BTEC Diploma - Health and Social Care	Passed

September 2006- May 2011: St. Richard's Catholic College - GCSEs

Subject	Grade
Science	A
Additional Science	В
Maths	В
English	В
History	В
Religious Education	В

#### Links:

Name	url
Github	https://github.com/Morgscode
Personal website	https://luke-morgan.com